Guide to the Department of Religious Studies, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Religious Studies, Yale University, records
1900-2006
RU 420
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19.0
(19 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, financial statements, contracts, reports, minutes, exams, papers, lectures, statistics, and student and personnel files documenting the Yale Department of Religious Studies. Topics include committees and councils; religious services; faculty; student performance and activity; curriculum and course development; admissions; financial aid; fellowships and scholarships; and dissertations.
Yale University. Department of Religious Studies
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, financial statements, contracts, reports, minutes, exams, papers, lectures, statistics, and student and personnel files documenting the Yale Department of Religious Studies. Topics include committees and councils; religious services; faculty; student performance and activity; curriculum and course development; admissions; financial aid; fellowships and scholarships; and dissertations.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Religion -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Religion; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of Religious Studies
- Minutes of faculty meetings, 1933-1949; Accession 1949-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Minutes of faculty meetings
    - 1933 Jun -1941 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1941 Sep -1949 Jun (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Records, circa 1900-1988; Accession 1990-A-017
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2024
  - Graduate School Correspondence
    - 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1961-1962, Faculty of Religion (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1962-1963, Faculty of Religion (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1962-1963, Discussion on Grad. Program (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Departmental, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reorganization and Council, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Grad. Dept. of Religion - Minutes, 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Department Meetings, Permanent Officers, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Department Meetings, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Department Chairmen, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Graduate School Memos, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graduate School Memos, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sent by D.R.S., 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Inter-Office Communications, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Records, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Class Schedules, Office Hours, Staff - Dept., 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Directory - Y.D.S. and G.S., 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Student Directive re: Brochure, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Directives to Students, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Directives to Graduate Faculty: Changes in Regulations, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Directives to Faculty, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Directives to Graduate Faculty: Dissertation Time Limit, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Graduate School Directives, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Procedures and Regulations, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Forms
    - Language Examination, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Authorization for Hanuscripts, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Advance Credit, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Course Drop, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Admissions, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Summer Research Support, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Junior Faculty Summer Research, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Registration Forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Student Record Forms, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Sample Forms, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Faculty Appointment, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Travel Expense Policy Records, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Travel Report, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Departmental Development, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - BUDGETS, PROGRAMS AND PROJECTS
    - Finances, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Statements, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Budget
      - 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Review, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Toll Call Authorization, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Maintenance Contracts, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Advisory Committee Report, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Buddhist Studies Conference- Vancouver, B.C., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - College Curriculum Policies, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Committee on History of Religions, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Computer, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Concilium on International Studies, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Graduate Programs in Other Schools, 1953-1958 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Joint Appointments, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Leaves, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Library, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Meeks Report, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - NDEA Statement - Jun (Personnel Data), 1968 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - NDEA Report, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - New Language Requirements, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Newspaper Publications, etc., 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Old Testament Discussions, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Philosophy of Religion, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Pierson, George W. re: National Endowment for the Humanities, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Priorities Display, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Sanskrit, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Selective Service Veterans' Administration, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Scholarly Publications Committee, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Senior Major Seminar, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - "Tasks and Strategies" Working Paper, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - "Tasks and Strategies" Paper Responses, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Theological Colloquiums, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Urban Studies, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Vassar - Yale, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Welch Study (Completed), 1954-1970 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Women Scholars in Religion, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Woodstock Project, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - YDS/Woodstock Consultations, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - SEARCH COMMITTEES, DIVINITY SCHOOL
    - Provost - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 95 - 97)
    - Misc. - Correspondence, Memos, Personal, Vitae, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 98 - 99)
    - Appointments Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - American Religious History, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Chaplain Search Committee (3 folders), 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 102 - 104)
    - Hebrew Bible/ OT Search, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Hebrew Language and Literature Search, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - History of Religion Search Committee, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Dept. of Religion: Reports, Historical, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - History of American Religion, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Interprofessional Education at Yale, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Islamic Religion: Affirmative Action, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Islamic Religion Search, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Islamic Search - 2nd Step, letters, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Islamic Religion Search Committee, 1977-1983 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Judaic Studies Candidates, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Philosophy/ Theology, Philosophy of Religion, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Schools Looking for Teachers, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Sociology of Religion Replacement, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - The Sunday Service in Battell, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - R.S./Y.D.S Executive Committee-Divinity School
    - 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Divinity School: Faculty, Staff, Executive Committee, 1972-1981 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Divinity School: Refations, 1969-1980 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Divinity School Relationships, 1972-1985 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - GRADUATE STUDIES COUNCIL, FACULTY
    - Council on Graduate Studies in Relieion of ACLS
      - 1947-1949 (Box 4, Folder 129)
      - 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 130)
      - Minutes (copies), 1948-1955 (Box 4, Folder 131)
      - 1950-1961 (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - 1960-1968 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Graduate Council on Religious Studies
      - Meetings, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - Constitution, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 137)
      - 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - 1967-1979 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Board of Permanent Officers, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Departmental Assembly, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Executive Committee - Faculty Minute Book, 1957-1963 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Graduate School - Department, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Committee on Graduate Studies - Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Graduate Faculty Minutes
      - 1946-1956 (Box 4, Folder 149)
      - 1957 (Box 4, Folder 150)
      - 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 151)
      - 1963-1975 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Faculty: Advisors, etc., 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Faculty Meetings, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Planning 1968, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Committee on the Graduate Program, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Committee on Graduate Studies- History, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Invoices, approved, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - D.R.S. Notes, Correspondence and Reports, 1954-1972 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - D.R.S. Minutes- Sep, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - D.R.S. Mimeographed Material, 1st Drafts I, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - D.R.S. Mimeographed Material, 1st Drafts II, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Graduate School Memos, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Grad. School Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Grad. School Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - General Correspondence
      - 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 168)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 169)
      - 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - LECTURES, UNDERGRADUATE COURSES, EXAMS and PAPERS
    - Xeroxed items, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - Lectures: Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Departmental Lectures, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Greenberg and Goshen-Gottstein, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - Hillman Lecture, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - Lectures, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - National Student Bioethics Conference, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Para-Curriculum Committee, 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Pearson Lecture, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Policy Papers: University Lectureships, 1959-1966 (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Postering the Campus For Lectures, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - Posters, undated (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - Special Lecture Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Special Lectures, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Special Lectures - Memos, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Suggested Lectures, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - Suggested Lectures, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    - Women's Spirituality in the Middle Ages, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    - Woodward Lectureships - Mitchell, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - Seminar on Teaching of Religion
    - 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    - 1962 (Box 6, Folder 239)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - DRS Undergraduate Program/Courses-Catalog Copies
    - 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 241)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 243)
    - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 245)
    - 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 246)
    - Committee Report, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 247)
    - Syllabi, 1961-1968 (Box 6, Folder 248)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 249)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 250 - 251)
    - 1969 Jan (Box 6, Folder 252)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - Courses
    - Course Reading Lists, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - Course Outlines (Previous Years), 1953-1963 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - Courses, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 256)
    - Course Outlines - Study and Reading Guides, 1971-1976 (Box 7, Folder 257)
    - R.S. 222: New Testament History and Lit., 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 258)
    - Exam - Outlines, Evaluation, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 259)
    - R.S. 60b: Buddhist Modernism, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 260)
    - R.S. 74b: Jewish Ethics, Leiman, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - R.S. 83b: Hasidism and Its Opposition, Levine, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 262)
    - R.S. 112: Papers, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - R.S. 112a: Exam Books and Papers, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - R.S. 112: Exam Books, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - R.S. 130b: Exam Books, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 266)
    - Final Papers and Journals - Psychology of Religion, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 267)
    - R.S. 197b: Final Papers and Journals, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 268)
    - R.S. 203a: Exam Books, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 269)
    - R.S. 203a: Exam Books, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 271)
    - R.S. 203a: Exam Questions, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 272)
    - R.S. 210b: Papers, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 273)
    - R.S. 211b: Adler- Law, Narrative and Israel's Harlotry, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 274)
    - R.S. 220b: Meeks- New Testament History and Literature, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 275)
    - R.S. 222a: Baskin- Jewish Experience in Europe, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 276)
    - R.S. 231a: Rudemann, Papers, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 277)
    - R.S. 234b: Meeks, Papers, undated (Box 7, Folder 278)
    - R.S. 237a: Baskin, Papers, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 279)
    - R.S. 237b: Septimus, Papers, undated (Box 7, Folder 280)
    - R.S. 244a: Granakoplos- Renaissance Humanism, undated (Box 7, Folder 281)
    - R.S. 248a: McLaughlin- Reformation Europe 1500-1600, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 282)
    - R.S. 291a: Katz- Contemporary Jewish History, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 283)
    - R.S. 292a: Katz- 20th Century Jewish Thought, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 284)
    - R.S. 304b: Mullin- American Religious Experience in Liberal Century, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 285)
    - R.S. 333b: Liberles- Modern Jewish Movements, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 286)
    - R.S. 378a: Frei/Porter, Exams, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 287)
    - R.S. 433b: Exams and Papers, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 288)
    - R.S. 456b: Course Improvement Forms, undated (Box 7, Folder 289)
    - R.S. 851b: Frei/Hamlin, Papers, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 290)
  - GRADUATE COURSES
    - Course Development, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 291)
    - Graduate Catalog Copy
      - 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 292)
      - 1962 Apr (Box 8, Folder 293)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 294)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 295)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 296)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 297)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 298)
      - 1967 Jan (Box 8, Folder 299)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 300)
      - 1968-1969 Bulletin (Box 8, Folder 301)
      - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 302)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 303)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 304)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 305)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 306)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 307)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 308)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 309)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 310)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 311)
    - Graduate Course Offerings (Box 8, Folder 312)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 313)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 314)
      - 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 315)
    - Courses: Renumbering, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 316)
    - Course Statistics
      - 1971 and before (Box 8, Folder 317)
      - 1968-1982 (Box 8, Folder 318)
      - Fall 1979 (Box 8, Folder 319)
      - Spring 1980 (Box 8, Folder 320)
      - Fall 1980 (Box 8, Folder 321)
      - Spring 1981 (Box 8, Folder 322)
      - 2nd Semester 1981 Updates (Box 8, Folder 323)
      - Fall 1981 (Box 8, Folder 324)
      - Spring 1982 (Box 8, Folder 325)
      - Fall 1982 (Box 8, Folder 326)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 327)
      - Spring 1983 (Box 8, Folder 328)
      - Fall 1983 (Box 8, Folder 329)
      - Spring 1984 (Box 8, Folder 330)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 331)
  - GRADUATE APPLICANTS, REGISTRATION, RATINGS, SCHEDULES AND GRADES
    - Enrollment, 1941-1952 (Box 9, Folder 332)
    - Admissions A - L Corresp., 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 333)
    - Correspondence - Prospective Students
      - 1953-1954 (Box 9, Folder 334)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 335)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 9, Folder 336)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 337)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 338)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 339)
    - Graduate Registration, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 340)
    - Applicants, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 341)
    - Comprehensive Listing of Students, 1959-1970 (Box 9, Folder 342)
    - Rejected Applicants - Grad. School, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 343)
    - Prospective Students, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 344)
    - Lists of Students, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 345)
    - Graduate Students in Residence, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 346)
    - Inactive File, 1939-1959 (Box 9, Folder 347)
    - Addresses of Yale Graduates, 1930-1964 (Box 9, Folder 348)
    - Names and Addresses - Lists, 1962-1965 (Box 9, Folder 349)
    - Graduate Faculty Student Ratings
      - 1962 (Box 9, Folder 350)
      - 1963 (Box 9, Folder 351)
      - 1964 (Box 9, Folder 352)
      - 1965 (Box 9, Folder 353)
      - 1966 (Box 9, Folder 354)
      - 1967 (Box 9, Folder 355)
      - 1968 (Box 9, Folder 356)
      - 1969 (Box 9, Folder 357)
      - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 358)
    - Discussion Divisions, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 359)
    - Course Registrations, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 360)
    - Registration by Courses, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 361)
    - Course Schedules
      - 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 362)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 363)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 364)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 365)
    - Grade Sheets
      - 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 366)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 367)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 368)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 369)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 370)
  - GRADUATE: BIOGRAPHICAL and DISSERTATIONS
    - Biographical Sheets
      - 1962 (Box 10, Folder 371)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 372)
      - 1964 (Box 10, Folder 373)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 374)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 375)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 376)
    - Correspondence requesting info. from Ph. D recipients Yale D. of Rel., 1943-1948 (Box 10, Folder 377)
    - Correspondence re: Dissertation Precis (Box 10, Folder 378)
    - Dissertations - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 379)
    - Ph.D Committee (Box 10, Folder 380)
    - Dissertation Approval Forms (Box 10, Folder 381)
    - Dissertation Instruction Sheet (Box 10, Folder 382)
    - Procedure for the Ph.D - Sep (Box 10, Folder 383)
    - Dissertations in Progress (Box 10, Folder 384)
    - Graduate Studies Council: Dissertations in Progress Elsewhere (Harvard, Vanderbilt)
    - Dissertations
      - 1960 May (Box 10, Folder 385)
      - 1961 May (Box 10, Folder 386)
      - 1961 Oct (Box 10, Folder 387)
      - 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 388)
      - 1962 Sep (Box 10, Folder 389)
      - 1963 Apr (Box 10, Folder 390)
      - 1963 Sep (Box 10, Folder 391)
      - In Progress, 1953-1964 (Box 10, Folder 392)
      - 1964 Apr (Box 10, Folder 393)
      - 1964 Sep (Box 10, Folder 394)
      - In Progress, 1965-1970 (Box 10, Folder 395)
      - 1965 Apr (Box 10, Folder 396)
      - 1965 Sep (Box 10, Folder 397)
      - 1966 Apr (Box 10, Folder 398)
      - 1966 Aug (Box 10, Folder 399)
      - 1966 Dec (Box 10, Folder 400)
      - 1967 Apr (Box 10, Folder 401)
      - 1967 Aug (Box 10, Folder 402)
      - 1967 Dec (Box 10, Folder 403)
      - 1968 Apr (Box 10, Folder 404)
      - 1968 Aug (Box 10, Folder 405)
      - 1968 Dec (Box 10, Folder 406)
      - 1969 Apr (Box 10, Folder 407)
      - 1969 Aug (Box 10, Folder 408)
      - 1970 Apr (Box 10, Folder 409)
      - 1971 Apr (Box 10, Folder 410)
      - 1973 Feb (Box 10, Folder 411)
      - 1973 May (Box 10, Folder 412)
      - 1973 Oct (Box 10, Folder 413)
    - Ph.D's with Dissertation Title, 1961-1970 (Box 10, Folder 414)
    - Dissertation Titles, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 415)
    - Dissertation Titles, 1953-1960 (Box 10, Folder 416)
    - Humanities - Rel. Studies Ph.D, 1900-1967 (Box 10, Folder 417)
    - Ph.D's - Dept. of Religion, 1924-1963 (Box 10, Folder 418)
    - Ph.D's - Religion, 1930-1967 (Box 10, Folder 419)
    - List of Graduates according to fields, Dept. of Religion, 1927-1959 (Box 10, Folder 420)
    - Recommended for M.A. Degree, 1962-1969 (Box 10, Folder 421)
    - Master of Philosophy Degree, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 422)
    - Candidates for Degrees, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 423)
    - Requests for Advanced Standing (Box 10)
      - 1962 May (Box 10, Folder 424)
      - 1963 Sep (Box 10, Folder 425)
      - 1964 (Box 10, Folder 426)
      - 1965 (Box 10, Folder 427)
    - Advanced Standing, 1966 January (Box 10, Folder 428)
  - FINANCIAL AID, FELLOWSHIPS and ENDOWMiENTS
    - Assistants in Instruction - Fellows
      - 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 429)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 430)
      - 1956-1960 (Box 11, Folder 431)
    - Connecticut State Fellowships, 1966-1969 (Box 11, Folder 432)
    - Fulbright Fellowship Program, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 434)
    - Hartford Seminary Foundation
      - 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 436)
    - Humanities Foundation, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 441)
    - Lilly Endowment, Inc., 1956-1968 (Box 11, Folder 444)
    - Post-Doctoral Fellows, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 445)
    - Applicants: Post-Doctoral Fellowships, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 446)
    - Presbyterian Graduate Fellowships, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 447)
    - Riggs Chair Candidates, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 448)
    - Riggs: Possible Appointments at Jr. Level, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 449)
    - Rockefeller Doctoral Fellowships
      - 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 450)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 451)
      - 1963 (Box 11, Folder 452)
      - Nominations, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 453)
      - Nominations, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 454)
      - Selection Committee, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 455)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 456)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 457)
    - Scholarship and Fellowship Applications, 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 458)
    - Sterling Nominations, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 459)
    - Summer Grants/Fellowships
      - 1962 (Box 11, Folder 460)
      - 1963 (Box 11, Folder 461)
      - 1964 (Box 11, Folder 462)
      - 1965 (Box 11, Folder 463)
      - 1966 (Box 11, Folder 464)
      - 1967 (Box 11, Folder 465)
      - 1968 (Box 11, Folder 466)
      - 1970 (Box 11, Folder 467)
    - Fellowships/Scholarship
      - 1961-1962 (Box 11, Folder 468)
      - American Council of Learned Societies, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 469)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 470)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 471)
    - Financial Awards: Students
      - 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 472)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 473)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 474)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 475)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 476)